Empty hallways, abandoned malls, deserted
playgrounds, these aren't just forgotten
places,
Their liminal spaces, the internet's
latest fascination, psychologists to find
Luminality as a state of
transition, a threshold between what
was and what will be.
These physical locations exist between
purposes, a waiting room before
an appointment or a school
During summer break. The absence
of people combined with familiar
structures creates a profound
Sense of eerie tranquility. Viewers
often report feelings of nostalgia,
a forgotten memory,
Or even a subtle, uncanny
dread when encountering them. The
internet amplified
This niche aesthetic, with community
sharing images that evoke this
unique unsettling beauty.
This online obsession even birthed
urban legends, most famously the
backrooms,
A never-ending labyrinth of yellow
walls and fluorescent hum, perhaps
the appeal lies in the
escape,
A digital space to confront
the anxieties of transition without
real-world risk.
Liminal spaces remind us that
beauty and sometimes dread can
be found in the quiet,
In-between moments of our built
world.